# **BRENDAN JANG**



## **OBJECTIVE**

To advance my career with a leading organization that will utilize my extensive software and programming knowledge while also allowing me to develop further as a professional

Proven talent for aligning business strategy and objectives with established software and development paradigms to achieve maximum operational impacts with minimum resource expenditures. Growth-focused thought leader known for expertise with Python and proficiency with C++, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL and Selenium. Exceptionally dedicated professional with keen interpersonal, communication, and organizational skills, as well as team leadership, process optimization, and resource allocation expertise.

#### **PROJECT HIGHLIGHTS**

- Haunted Mansion: Text based escape room game built using Python.
- PWGen: Generates and stores random passwords in a designated txt file.
- CodingResources: Personal website project for resources on learning how to code.
- Wasteagram: Mobile app inspired by Instagram to track daily waste in the food industry.
- *Splittrip*: Web app to keep track of supplies and purchases made by a group.
- JobScraper: Python script to scrape job boards for new jobs matching specific criteria.

More project examples

#### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- Data management
- Data analysis
- Strategy development

- Process optimization
- Relationship management
- Team leadership

- Problem solving
- Communication
- Collaboration

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SERRANO EYE CENTER MEDICAL GROUP, LOS ANGELES, CALIFORNIA, MARCH 2016 TO PRESENT

## MANAGER IN TRAINING, OCTOBER 2019 TO PRESENT

- Developed and implemented a new system for tracking and handling office income using Excel, which streamlined processes and increased office efficiency.
- Oversee the hiring and training of new and current employees in multiple departments, including IT, surgery, marketing, and billing, ensuring new hires were informed of best practices and policies.
- Led the process automation and revamping of calculating employee hours for payroll using Python file input/output, which reduced time spent on payroll and increased accuracy.
- Ensure office computers stayed up to date and healthy through routine software, hardware, and network checks, as well as proactively strategizing to prevent malfunctions.
- Provide guidance to current employees, helping build high-performing teams and driving department productivity.
- Demonstrated ability to optimize operations and lead teams in high-stress situations.

#### **BILLING MANAGER**, JULY 2018 TO PRESENT

- Managed a team of three, quickly and efficiently handling the medical billing process for Medicare, Medical, HMO, and Commercial claims.
- Assessed and identified unpaid and denied insurance claims using practice management reports and handled claim reprocessing and denial management effectively.
- Prepared and ran monthly reports aiming to identify and correct problem areas in the billing process, and developed strategies for improvement areas based on the reports.
- Spearheaded the implementation of new billing procedures that contributed to a 20.9% increase in net payments collected from insurance companies in 2019.

Brendan Jang Page 2

• Built a custom script that compared current and previous years' office income and flagged negative performance.

## SURGERY COORDINATOR, MARCH 2016 TO JULY 2018

- Liaised and coordinated with surgeons and ambulatory surgery centers to schedule patients for surgery, prioritizing high-risk cases and managing various patients simultaneously.
- Drove and increase in premium lens unit sales by 74%, resulting in 56% growth in net income from lenses during 2016 to 2018.
- Generated scripts for outpatient tests and procedures as ordered per physician.
- Responsible to continually monitor the schedule looking for inefficiencies, as well as strategizing for improvement.
- Informs office staff and distributes the schedule to the office and the other two facilities for surgery.

# **EDUCATION AND CREDENTIALS**

MASTER OF SCIENCE (M.Sc.) IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, IN PROGRESS
Georgia Tech University, Atlanta Georgia

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (B.Sc.) IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, 2021
Oregon State University, Corvallis, Oregon

# **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

Languages: English, Korean

Technical Proficiencies: Python, C++, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL, Selenium, Flask, Flutter/Dart

**Interests:** Fishing, Basketball (recreational), Weightlifting, Literature, Film